Preliminary Inventory of the Racho Petrov Papers, 1885-1916
Hoover Institution Archives
- Military Mutiny in Roussé and Silistra, 1887 - fomented by Tzarist Russia
  - A cable from Captain Ouvaliev to Major Racho Petroff, 1887 March 13, on leaving for Varna and then for Roussé to take possession of the Artillery (#57, original in Bulgarian)
  - A cable from Captain Ouvaliev to Major Racho Petroff, 1887 March 24-Captain Tzenov requests authorization to go on holiday (#58, original in Bulgarian)
  - A cable from Natchovitch, Minister of Forreign Affairs to Major Racho Petroff, expresses the opinion to stop new death sentences in order to avoid a foreign intervention, 1887 (#59, original in Bulgarian)
  - A description of the mutiny in Silistra by Kerekov (#60, in Bulgarian)
  - A cable from Captain Paprikoff, Chief of Staff to Major Racho Petroff, on changes in the high commands after the mutiny, 1887 (#61, in Bulgarian)
  - A cable from Captain Tzontchev to Major Racho Petroff, on the necessity to bring Kerekoff back from Silistra (#62, in Bulgarian)
  - A cable from Captain Ouvaliev to Captain Ivanoff, Sofia, on his dispute with Captain Nikiforoff and the inquiry on the alarm given in Shoumen, 1887 (#63, in Bulgarian)
  - A cable from the Regent Stamboulov to Major Racho Petroff, 1887 February 20, on not executing the death sentence against Bollman, because he is a foreign citizen (Russian) (#64, in Bulgarian)
  - A cable from Captain Drandarevski to Major Racho Petroff, on the destiny of the recruits who took part in the mutiny, and the answer of Major Racho Patroff: "let them return freely to their villages" (#65, in Bulgarian)
  - A cable from Captain Drandarevski from Silistra to Major Racho Petroff, on the troops from Silistra sent to Roussé with the ship "Golubtchik", 1887 March 27 (#66, in Bulgarian)